# GuilhermeDeMaio

Software Developer

#### contact

São Paulo - Brasil

+55 11 9 8393 2639

**9** guilherme\_nirev guilherme@nirev.org https://nirev.dev

**O**/nirev

**y**′nirev

in/nirev

#### languages

native portuguese fluent english basic french

## programming

Elixir, Java, Ruby, Javascript, C, Python, HTML, css, bash, Kafka, Spark, docker, monitoring tools

### interests

distributed systems, making a better world, data structures, music, martial arts, science fiction, fighting fascism

## about me

I've been developing software for over 10 years, from web apps to embedded platforms. During this time I've come to believe: - Empathy first, always - Trust is key - Less is more

On the tech side of things, I'm more of a backend/operations type, but I do dabble a bit on the frontend. I enjoy taking part and ownership of where and how applications are deployed and monitored.

I take pride in being part of team. I enjoy giving talks and getting to know people at conferences. I've been a team lead before, and I dislike the term "soft skills". Once you're in a position as such, those so called "soft" skills are exactly what is most important.

## recent experience

November 2017 - \*

Staff Engineer at Telnyx

Remote / Chicago - US

I joined Telnyx as an Elixir software developer tasked with building their new Call Control product, which is all about abstracting away telephony and providing APIs for interfacing with telephone calls. In a short timeframe I was the tech lead of the project, and have since been promoted to Staff Engineer. During this time I've been involved in:

- Building, deploying, monitoring and operaring the new product
- Shaping the product and roadmap together with Product Managers
- Talking to clients to understand use cases and provide guidance integrating with the API
- Supporting Sales and Marketing onboarding and bringing new customers
- Hiring, both Elixir and frontend engineers critical to product growth

September 2015 – September 2017

Senior Software Engineer at XERPA

São Paulo - Brazil

I joined the company as their first employee to help build the SaaS platform tackling HR bureaucracy in Brazil. We started from day-0 with Elixir and Phoenix on the backend, with the frontend initially in simple html/css/jquery. We eventually migrated the frontend to ClojureScript using a GraphQL API.

Among things I took part are:

- Bootstrapped the platform using Elixir, Phoenix, PostgreSQL, Terraform and Ansible
- Built libraries for: Auth, ElasticSearch, image manipulation, payment gateway integration
- Defining and prioritizing features together with product and business/sales teams.
- Interviewing "beta" clients to get a better understanding of the problems we needed to solve.
- Collaborating heavily with Customer Success team to help streamline client usage after signup
- Built a document distribution using OCR which greatly improved sales and customer satisfaction.

November 2012 – September 2015

#### Team Lead (Search and Analytics) at Elo7

São Paulo - Brazil

A marketplace with high traffic and transaction volume. The stack was based on Java, Ruby and Scala on AWS infrastructure. A fast paced environment, with agile practices, and focusing on delivering fast with quality. We measured and logged using StatsD, Graphite, and NewRelic, and deployed constantly. I was leading the Search and Analytics Team: a small team using Solr, Kafka and Spark to improve search and real time reports, and responsible for its infrastructure and pipeline tools.

#### past experiences details available upon request

04/2012 to 10/2012 - Intern at INRIA Paris-Roquencourt Paris - France
03/2011 to 09/2012 - Undergrad Researcher at USP - CHOReOS project São Paulo - Brazil
08/2010 to 02/2011 - Software Developer (C/C++) at RR Sistema Vitória/ES - Brazil
01/2009 to 12/2010 - Undergrad Intern at Multimedia and Network Research Lab
08/2008 to 12/2008 - Undergrad Intern at LASSY University of Luxembourg
03/2007 to 12/2007 - Undergrad Intern at NINFA laboratory Vitória/ES - Brazil

# education

2011–2014 Master in Computer Science 2005–2010 B.Sc. in Computer Science University of São Paulo - Brazil Federal University of Espírito Santo - Brazil